Everything that has a beginning has an end.
The Matrix Revolutions is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by Lilly Wachowski.
The human city of Zion defends itself against the massive invasion of the machines as Neo
fights to end the war at another front while also opposing the rogue Agent Smith.
Neo, played by Keanu Reeves.
Morpheus, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Trinity, played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
Agent Smith, played by Hugo Weaving.
Niobe, played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
The Oracle, played by Mary Alice.
The Matrix Revolutions is a 2003 American science fiction
action film written and directed by the Wachowskis.
It is the third in The Matrix film series, released
six months after the second film.
It stars Keanu Reeves, Laurence Fishburne, Carrie-Anne
Moss, Hugo Weaving and Jada Pinkett Smith.
The plot involves Neo and his allies as they fight to end the war between humanity
and the machines permanently while opposing the rogue Agent Smith.
The Matrix Revolutions was released worldwide on
November 5, 2003, by Warner Bros.
It was the first live-action feature film to be released in
both regular and IMAX theaters simultaneously.
It grossed $427 million, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film
of 2003, and received mixed reviews from critics.
A fourth film, The Matrix Resurrections, was released in 2021.
The film explores themes of dying and death,
rescue, future, mission, man vs machine.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.